hey Brett canteras here and right now
I'm going to show you the difference
between how I perform the low box squat
and the high box squat because I do them
differently so this right here um these
are adjustable I got them from Elite FTS
um this is about 11 in high and this is
I believe 16 in high so there's about a
5 in inch differential here and uh um so
I I have the box angled to where it's
not straight it's diagonal here so right
now I'm just going to sit down well
notice the back of my calves are
touching the Box okay I sit straight
down I have a narrow stance well it's
not too narrow but it's not wide and
then I come straight up notice I don't
ever plot down I land very gently I like
to rock back just a little bit which
I'll talk about in a second then I come
up okay that's a low box squat and then
the high box squat I'm going to get a
wider
stance um calves touching the box and
now I'm going to sit way back and spread
the knees so um I initiate by sitting
the hips back like that so imagine
someone has a rope tied around your
waist sit back and then down like this
keep the knees out and I have a little
bit of a a pretty substantial for
forward trunk lean but notice the tibia
right now the tibia is vertical it's
straight up so lean in get an arch stand
up sit back spread the
knees come up okay so the things um that
you need to be aware of when you box
squat you never want to plop because if
you plop down you've got all that Force
crashing down which creates a lot of
stress to the posterior tissues um so
you don't want to do that don't crash
down always land nice and gently and
then the other thing is this is the most
important thing see my lumbar spine has
a nice Arch here you never ever want to
relax the lumbar spine and let your body
go into flexion if you do this you will
hurt yourself keep that Arch and um you
know get a nice brace
and then um pause for a second and then
explode up that way you get more
starting strength and you take the
elastic mechanism out of the lift a
little bit so um box squat is a very
safe exercise as long as you pay
attention to the the form and do it the
correct way so that's the difference
between a low box squat and a high box
squat